Daniel Wierdsma

O github.com/d-wierdsma

1 +1 (519) 635 4151

Professional Summary

Site Reliability Engineer with five years of experience working in small teams that specialize in building reliable largescale infrastructures to handle millions of users. A hard-working and lifelong learner proficient with the big 3 cloud providers and associated container orchestration tools (ECS, EKS, GKE, AKS).

Work Experience

Site Reliability Engineer II | Mattermost

May 2022 to May 2023

- Maintained over 15,000 production Mattermost workspaces in multiple Kubernetes clusters with 99.9% uptime.
- Architected Mattermost deployment of production Kubernetes services to be managed by over 150 ArgoCD Applications.
- Designed custom Helm Charts to allow other development teams to manage their services in a GitOps way.
- Utilized Mattermost Operator to deploy, upgrade, and destroy Mattermost workspaces in multiple Kubernetes
- Implemented cost cutting procedures in multiple AWS accounts to reduce Mattermost Cloud spending by 40%.
- Led initiative to convert Mattermost Calls Recorder to be a cloud-native application and host it within Kubernetes clusters.
- Responded to high-priority system incidents and outages during weekly on-call rotations, improving system availability by 15%.

DevOps Engineer | Daylight

May 2020 to May 2022

- O Planned migration of AWS ECS services to Azure AKS for all Daylight environments.
- Designed architecture and deployment strategies for new Kubernetes environments in AKS.
- Maintained Shoppers Drug Mart COVID-19 testing and vaccination forms to over 3 million users.
- Migrated existing CloudFormation Troposphere scripts to Terraform to manage all new environments.
- Participated in SOC 2 Type 2 Certification and yearly audits.
- Maintained existing, and created new AWS environments for dedicated and multitenant clients.

DevOps Engineer | Tulip Retail

January 2019 to April 2020

- Designed an SFTP Automation Framework leverging AWS services to reduce client-onboarding time by 20%.
- O Built CI/CD frameworks for internal projects and all serverless applications through use of GitLab CI that automatically tests and deploys new changes.
- Designed new monitoring solution leveraging Prometheus, Thanos, Grafana, and Alertmanager.

Conference Speaker | AWS Summit Toronto 2019

October 2019

As a conference speaker in the Start-Up Booth at AWS Summit Toronto 2019 presented an **SFTP Automation design** that solved the problem of creating custom SFTP Virtual Machine instances for each new customer. This was achieved by leveraging many tools such as Transfer for AWS, Lambdas, DynamoDB, and SQS.

Development Experience

📽 DevOps Tools • Prometheus, Thanos, Grafana, Loki, Tempo, Istio, GitLab CI, Github Actions, NGINX, Bash, Git

· Kubernetes, Terraform, ArgoCD, Docker, Cloudflare, Packer, Helm, kOps, Teleport, KinD

∆ Environments AWS (5+ years), Azure (2+ years), GCP (2+ years), Amazon Linux, Ubuntu, Debian, macOS

Back End · Python, Go, Node.js, PHP

Databases • RDS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, CloudSQL, DynamoDB, Redis

■ Fundamentals · Cloud, GitOps, Microservices, CI/CD, Serverless Applications, Agile Development

Education

University of Waterloo Graduated in 2018